# ISMAIL OMODARA

## Software Engineer

## ismailomodara.io@gmail.com



#### About Me

A user-focused Software Engineer capable of conceptualising original ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex designs. Capable of working with product management and engineering to define and implement innovative solutions for the product, business direction, visuals, and experience.

## Experience

February 2020 - August 2022

#### Software Engineer (Frontend), Edenlife Inc.

Edenlife is a company that brings the convenience of room service to homes across Africa. It is the first of its kind.

- I provided engineering and front-end leadership to teammates through coaching and mentorship.
- I collaborated with a team of engineers, product managers and product designers to build and manage the Customer Relationship Management tool, used for everyday operations management.
- I had recurring collaborations with other team members to figure out useful user interfaces and experiences to enhance software systems.
- I worked on speed and usability optimisation for all software systems.

November 2020 - May 2022

## Product Engineer, NQLB Limited

NQLB is an organisation that provides software solutions as a service.

- I worked with a team of software engineers and business analysts to plan, design, test and maintain business applications built.
- I guided team development efforts toward successful project delivery and was also responsible for conducting user research to evaluate user feedback.
- I provided third-level support to business users Researched and e.
- I assisted in the collection and documentation of user requirements, and the development of user stories, estimates and work plans.
- I worked as a Product Designer to drive the creation of intuitive user experiences around different products.

February 2020 - June 2020

## Frontend Engineer, Init Africa

Init Africa is a startup that builds industry-specific software solutions.

- I worked with a team of three (as the sole Frontend Engineer) to build and manage the company's product, Element Photo.
- I pinpointed user experience issues to devise targeted suggestions for creating a cohesive user experience.

April 2019 - August 2019

#### Frontend Engineer, Fundall

Fundall is a platform that provides tools, education and business support needed to people.

- I worked with a Backend Engineer to develop the customer-facing web application.
- I worked on the landing page design for the platform to create awareness as to what the product offers.
- I executed all visual design stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering (including front-end development, design and branding).

October 2018 - March 2019

## Frontend Developer Intern, Cregital

Cregital is a digital agency that designs and creates digital experiences, with a track record of impeccable solutions across the world.

- I worked with a team of Product Designers and Backend Engineers to build a <u>Portfolio Creator</u>, allowing people with no code experience to design and publish a personal website.
- I collaborated with a team to build an **Email Signature** generator platform.
- I worked on developing and maintaining Frontend Code.
- I worked closely with the Frontend Team Lead to learn and perform assigned tasks.

## Tools & Technologies

Web HTML, CSS, SCSS, Vue, Vuex, Nuxt, Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

React, Next, Cypress

CI/CD

Netlify, Vercel

Node, ExpressJS, AdonisJS

Project Notion, Jira, Google Docs/Sheets,

Management Trello

## Education

May 2015 **B.Sc Computer Engineering,**- February 2020 **Obafemi Awolowo University** 

May 2022 <u>Google Project Management.</u> (In review)

- October 2022

Dec 2020 React Nanodegree, Udacity.

- February 2021

